

BÁLINT FARAGÓ

Senior Project Manager, PMP, MBA

balintfarago@gmail.com +36-30/825-3104 Szentendre, Hungary 25 Dec 1985, Budapest

I'm a PMP-certified Project Manager with 8+ years experience in leading all phases of diverse projects with multiple teams. I have strong technical knowledge and experience in IT transformation, greenfield developments, banking and telco solutions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

09/2022 - Present

F. HOFFMANN - LA ROCHE AG (contractor, remote)

Senior Project Manager

- Managing a global team, while working fully remote
- Coordinating the implementation of a communication system
- Onboarding multiple countries in North America, LATAM, EMEA and **APAC** regions
- Creating a test strategy and coordinating testing
- Providing global support and holding end-user trainings.

06/2022 - 09/2022 VODAFONE HUNGARY (contractor, hybrid)

Scrum Master/ Product Owner

- Managed all live consumer and enterprise-related issues in the Transformation Program
- Worked closely with the business representatives and the development team, prioritizing the backlog and planning sprints
- Managed the updates, comments and changes in JIRA
- Coaching the team on agile practices and processes

09/2019 - 06/2022

Senior Project Manager / Consultant

- Delivered multiple projects in parallel in a giant, 5-year long digital **Transformation Program**
- Implemented business requirements in a newly created billing system before migrating 2 million customers from the legacy system.
- Successfully complied with the ever changing legal requirements of sending invoices to the Tax Authority
- Managed the implementation of a new system that provides data to the Vodafone self-service portal and sends daily extracts to partners

08/2018 - 08/2019 BUDAPEST BANK

Senior Project Manager

Digital Loan and Account Opening (80 project members, 8 systems)

- Managed a project with an enormous business focus on becoming the 1st bank to provide commodity credit online
- Created a passionate team willing to devote free time and weekends in order to deliver successfully
- Worked with waterfall, agile and kanban methodologies in parallel
- Overcame obstacles coming from a difficult environment
- Managed a budget of 600M HUF and reported weekly to Deputy CEO

NFC Payment (13 project members, 4 systems)

- Implemented NFC payment for Android users of the bank
- Led a virtual team (Norwegian supplier, Mastercard, internal team)
- Led the SLA contracting process and negotiated with the partner
- Coordinated the project with a strong focus on customer experience

05/2014 - 08/2018

Project Manager

Mortgage Refinancing (20 project members, 6 systems)

- Besides managing the project, I was also tasked with the Business
 Analyst role to create the business specification
- Planned testing, trained new testers, tracked and controlled bugs during UAT and reported them weekly to the CFO

Mortgage Proposal Module (12 project members, 3 systems)

- Replaced the old mortgage calculation Excel file with a modern web application of 150 internal and 1500 external users
- Decreased mortgage calculation time from 5 minutes to 30 seconds
- Received an award for successfully organizing parallel development and testing that significantly reduced delivery time and assured quality

Oracle Financials Implementation (80 project members, 12 systems)

- We upgraded the then version of Oracle and brought it on premise
- Coordinated and supervised the internal team members, all 10 different vendor companies and the whole Oracle team
- Organized parallel testing and training for ops to ensure target date

EDUCATION

2018 - 2020	Budapest University of Technology and Economics - MBA Thesis: The Impact of Fintech on the Operation of Financial Institutions
2004 - 2009	Corvinus University of Budapest – Information Technology

COMPUTER SKILLS

- Project Management (MS Project, HP QC, JIRA, Trello)
- Programming (PHP, SQL, Javascript, Java, Android)

LANGUAGE SKILLS

- English (Advanced level)
- German (Intermediate level)

CERTIFICATES

- PMP
- Certified Scrum Master
- Cloud (Azure, AWS)
- ITIL Foundation v3
- ISTQB